Zackery J. Arsement

(409) 673-0734 | Beaumont, TX 77625 | zarsement@hotmail.com | https://github.com/ZackeryArsement | https://www.linkedin.com/in/zackery-arsement/ | https://zackeryarsement.github.io/webPortfolio/

Career Summary

Full stack web developer with 7+ years of software experience. Background in mechanical engineering in the oil and gas industry which relied heavily on technical problem solving. Technologies used in recent projects included React, MySQL, MongoDB, express, Node.js and Apollo graphQL to create interactive applications. Both projects utilized Phaser 3 to implement fun and interactive and responsive games into the application. Looking for a junior level full stack web developer position that constantly pushes the boundary of the software industry.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Aug 2017 - Dec 2020

B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, GPA: 3.426/4.000

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

The Coding Bootcamp at UT Austin

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate, Final Grade: A+

Skills

ReactJS, Javascript, MySQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Express.js, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Github, Heroku, SolidWorks, OpenFOAM, C#, Unity Game Engine, MATLAB, Robot-C, Arduino, Python

Projects

Take-Me-To-Your-Leader | https://github.com/ZackeryArsement/TakeMeToYourLeader | http://take-me-to-vour-leader.herokuapp.com/

- · Summary: Light-hearted sentence builder browser game that uses a database to persist user's progress
- · Role: Game concept designer, front and back end game developer
- · Tools: Javascript, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, Node.is, HTML, CSS, Phaser 3

Rise-N'-Thrive | https://github.com/romeodixonll/Rise-N-Thrive | https://risenthrive.herokuapp.com/

- · Summary: All inclusive morning application to help users start their day
- · Role: Mini-games developer using React and Phaser 3. Front and back end
- · Tools: ReactJS, Javascript, Express, MongoDB, Node.js, CSS, Phaser 3

Let's-Get-Outta-Here | https://github.com/ZackeryArsement/projectOne | https://zackeryarsement.github.io/projectOne/

- · Summary: Travel application that provides a list of nearby cities and their weather
- · Role: Front end developer for 'Results' page; integrated Restful API's to the application
- · Tools: Javascript, JQuery, RestfulAPI's, Node.js, HTML, CSS

Experience

UT Coding Bootcamp – JavaScript Full-Stack Course (Austin, TX)

Dec 2021 – Mar 2022

- · Integrated packages such as handlebars and Phaser 3 to create a fully functional browser game that stored user data in a database
- · Utilized public API's to create an application that provides nearby cities, their distance, and their weather
- · Created several applications that use express is and node is that allow for smooth, dynamic web applications

Wrench Time Analyst for Kelly Services at DOW Chemical (Orange, TX)

Jun 2021 - Nov 2021

- · Shadowed crews such as E&I, mechanic, and pipefitters during daily and turnaround schedules for all DOW Units
- · Planned process optimizations with engineering leadership such as scheduling, job setups, and permitting
- · Extracted thousands of data entries to provide management with clear E&I, mechanical, and pipefitting insight

NASA Mechanical Engineer – Senior Design Project (Austin, TX)

Fall 2020

- · Developed an exercise device in a zero-g environment for NASA, alongside 3 team members
- · Utilized SolidWorks to design, model and perform fatigue/stress analysis on device
- · Ensured ergonomic features and prioritized safety for human use

Catering Manager, Rockin' A Café (Beaumont, TX)

Jun 2017 – Jun 2021

- · Led catering events for small and large scale events (15-1500 meals)
- · Participated in benefits for local families during natural disasters and medical fundraisers

VEX Robotics (Collegiate World Participant) (Austin, TX)

Aug 2013 - Apr 2018

- · Developed fully autonomous, 1-minute long autonomous programs using Robot-C
- · Collaborated in design and building of intricate, competitive robots